<div>
	<p>The LUCI lab maintains this repository of tech reports as a reference site for affiliated researchers to use as a bibiliographic source.  To have your publication included in the tech report repository it must be sponsored by a faculty member in LUCI, it must not be encumbered by a copyright and it must be formatted in pdf with a standard cover sheet.  All tech reports are assigned a number for tracking.  All work published here is covered under the "<a href="asfunction:_root.jumpToURLNewWindow,http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/us/"> Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 United States License</a>" This is the same copyright that the Science Commons and journal "Nature" use.</p> 
	<p>To submit a paper to the tech report repository have your faculty sponsor contact Professor Patterson.</p>

<p><a href="asfunction:_root.jumpToURLNewWindow,websiteContent/repository/techreports/2009/LUCI-2009-004.pdf">LUCI-2009-004</a> <b>Print This Paper, Kill A Tree: Environmental Sustainability
				as a Research Topic for Human-Computer Interaction</b> by Dourish, P.</p>
<p><a href="asfunction:_root.jumpToURLNewWindow,websiteContent/repository/techreports/2009/LUCI-2009-003.pdf">LUCI-2009-003</a> <b>LUCI Lab Annual Report 2008-2009</b> by Patterson, D.J.</p>
<p><a href="asfunction:_root.jumpToURLNewWindow,websiteContent/repository/techreports/2009/LUCI-2009-002.pdf">LUCI-2009-002</a> <b>Measuring Display Interaction in Presence of Context Information</b> by Liu, K.,  et.al.</p>
<p><a href="asfunction:_root.jumpToURLNewWindow,websiteContent/repository/techreports/2009/LUCI-2009-001.pdf">LUCI-2009-001</a> <b>Status On Display: A Field Trial of Nomatic*Viz</b> by Ding, X.,  et.al.</p>
<p><a href="asfunction:_root.jumpToURLNewWindow,websiteContent/repository/techreports/2008/LUCI-2008-002.pdf">LUCI-2008-002</a> <b>Understanding the Digital Divide in Southern Africa</b> by Aiyelokun, T.,  et.al.</p>
<p><a href="asfunction:_root.jumpToURLNewWindow,websiteContent/repository/techreports/2008/LUCI-2008-001.pdf">LUCI-2008-001</a> <b>The Technology Garden</b> by Lee, C., Hornick, B., et. al.</p>
</div> 
