<div>
<p>In the 1980’s, the idea of the computer was reinvented; the advent of graphical user interfaces allowed computers to become consumer devices, and radically transformed our ideas of what computers could be and could do. At the start of the twenty-first century, a similar transformation is under way, as mobile and ubiquitous technologies create opportunities for radically new forms of interaction with each other and with the world around us, mediated by interactive systems. We envision a world in which technology can not just help us to be more effective, but can also enrich the social, cultural, and aesthetic fabric of everyday life.</p>
<p> LUCI, the Laboratory for Ubiquitous Computing and Interaction, serves as a focal point for research that follows from this vision. Our group of researchers are interested in the challenges of designing, using, and understanding the elements of a ubiquitous computing world.  Some of these different facets include computing in the face of mobile computers and mobile users, understanding and exploring new patterns of socio-technical behavior, and the design and construction of technology which supports ubiquitous computing.  </p> 
<p> Administratively, LUCI exists in the <a href="asfunction:_root.jumpToURLNewWindow,http://www.ics.uci.edu/informatics/">Department of Informatics</a>, a department in the <a href="asfunction:_root.jumpToURLNewWindow,http://www.ics.uci.edu">Donald Bren School of Information and Computer Sciences</a> at the <a href="asfunction:_root.jumpToURLNewWindow,http://www.uci.edu">University of California at Irvine</a>.  We are <a href="asfunction:_root.jumpToURLNewWindow, http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;q=E+Peltason+Dr+%26+Los+Trancos+Dr,+Irvine,+Orange,+California+92617,+United+States&amp;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&amp;sspn=44.793449,93.164063&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;cd=1&amp;geocode=FTJXAQIdzt_5-A&amp;ll=33.645939,-117.841973&amp;spn=0.011557,0.022745&amp;t=h&amp;z=16&amp;layer=c&amp;cbll=33.64229,-117.84197&amp;panoid=U7dM0uMFswk5r2aaPA5L7w&amp;cbp=1,0,,0,5">physically located</a> in Irvine and Orange County, between Los Angeles and San Diego, in beautiful Southern California, USA.  Our lab is located on the 5th floor of the new Donald Bren Hall on the UCI campus.  </p>
</div> 


